立法會主席。
要要熟要要幾日？
發現。
石禮謙議員就政府賬目委員會第六十三號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙。Thank you, Mr. President.
on behalf of the public accounts committee.
我有啲榮幸，要表達我報告號碼63今日。
The committee has, as in the past, decided to hold hearings on those chapters covered by the director of audits' report number 63, which, in our views, contain more serious allegations of irregularities and shortcomings.
委員會的報告，表達今日覆蓋我們的結論和建議，關於三個四個章節選出。
委員會已決定延遲表決全報告，針對選項章節有關空中交通管制及相關服務的管理，以讓我們有更多時間考慮報告中提出的問題，以及有關。
Of the information provided by the witnesses, I now succinctly report the conclusions and recommendations on the three chapters covered in this report of number sixty three. First, I would like to speak on the new civil aviation department headquarters.
The committee considers it inexcusable and condemns the Civil Aviation Department and the Architectural Services Department that, in implementation of the new CAD headquarters, CAD had deliberately
overridden the administration internal mechanism to regulate the use of public money. ASD had failed to perform its role as the project director of the project to ensure CAD's compliance with the relevant regulations and guidelines.
undermine the administration's internal mechanisms of checks and balances. This is evidenced by the numerous incidents of non-compliance with the approved schedules of accommodations and the requirements of the relevant government circulars in the procurement of new furniture.
和設備在總部。
The committee also deplored the director general of civil aviation, who had wilfully neglected his responsibilities and duty to provide complete, accurate and not misleading information to the legislative council for funding approval. It is evidence.
由The fact that CAD had turned a future provision of 1,500 square metres of area, which was reserved for future expansion beyond 2025, into a present construction in the new headquarters.
這批重要資訊從未在文件中提及，給相關立法委員會、公眾工作小組和財政委員會。委員會指出，除了已採取和將要採取的改善措施外，
TAD和ASD， to strengthen internal control to ensure compliance with the relevant government's regulations and guidelines. In the future, the secretary for transport and housing has requested the director general of civil aviation to provide a detailed report to review the irregularity.
on the implementation of the project.
The TAB will look into details of events in depth to see if there is room for procedural improvement apart from those recommended in the audit report.
如果有任何 misconduct of staff, THB will follow in will follow up in accordance with established procedures and take appropriate administrative or disciplinary action where necessary. The committee wishes to be informed of the report and any.
follow up actions to be taken by THP. The second and third subject, which I will briefly report, are related to the provision of long term care services and health services for the elderly. The committee recognises the important contribution of the elderly population to the community.
and consider that it is incumbent for the administration to provide appropriate long-term care and health services for all the elderly who are in need.
On the subject of long-term care services for the elderly, the committee expresses grave concern and finds it unacceptable that the Labour and Welfare Bureau and the Social Welfare Department have failed in making sufficient efforts in discharging their responsibilities in the provision of long.
長-term care services for the elderly, and have not maximised the effective use of the limited subsidised long-term care places available. With an ageing population, the demand for long-term care services for the elderly has been and will be growing. Despite the administration has adopted
The policy of ageing in place as the core, the committee expresses grave concern that the labour and welfare bureau and the social welfare department have not provided.
sufficient resources, ancillary and support services for the provision of community care services.
委員會也表達深切 concern，並認為不接受關於不足的居屋護理設施。
as at end August two thousand and four there were some thirty one thousand elderly on the central waiting list but there were only twenty six thousand subsidised places resulting in a long waiting time of thirty six months for subsidised care and attention place at a.
預防或contract residential care home for the elderly， the committee wishes
expect。
Apologies. The committee expresses deep regrets and sadness in 2013 to 2014. The number of elderly on the waiting list who have passed away while waiting for residential care places have reached 5,700.
委員會希望，除加強所有可能措施以增加提供社區護理服務和居屋護理服務外，行政應加快擬定中長期和長遠規劃，以制定長遠的護理政策，以照顧長者。
Taking into account the projections on the proportion and growth of elderly population and their needs.
委員會 notes that the administration have tasked the Elderly Commission in 2014 to prepare the Elderly Services Program Plan within two years.
我 now turn to the third subject on the provision of health services for the elderly.
委員會表達強烈擔憂，，雖然撥款給衞生及醫院局提供長者醫療服務的資源，但這些資源並未被充分利用及管理得當，並有效地提供及時、高效及。
Value for money services for the elderly. This is evidenced by the long waiting time for first time assessment at the elderly health cares, the low enrolment rates for the medical practitioners and the Chinese medical practitioners under the elderly health care voucher scheme, as well.
作為一般增加等待時間， for routine cases of elderly patients at specialist outpatients clinics， the committee urges the Department of Health to conduct a comprehensive review on the elderly care.
modes of operation to better cope with the growth in service demand arising from an ageing population. The hospital authority is also urged to consider measures to better cater for increasing healthcare needs of the elderly patients, to keep the situation under constant review and.
要 revisit where and when necessary the need to redesignate geriatrics presently a sub specialty under the medicine specialty as a separate specialty. Lastly, Mr. President, I wish to record my appreciation of the contribution.
由成員所提出的建議，我們的感謝也延伸到出席聽證會的證人。
I would also like to express our gratitude to the Director of Audit and his colleagues for their unfailing support. Lastly, but not the least, and also our appreciation to the Secretariat who have given us great support. Thank you.
答案，首讀。